

Semyon Kovardaev

Frontend Developer



Tech stack

- TypeScript, React, Next
- SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, MUI
- Npm, Yarn, Webpack, Vite
- GitHub, Bitbucket, Fork
- Figma
- Node, Express, Nest
- Mongo, SQL, Mongoose, Prisma

Education

2023

Fullstack Development

HTML Lessons

2021

Web Development

HTML Academy

2019-2020

Frontend Development

Netology

2009-2014

Technical English

Russian Technological University

2008-2013

Engineering Management

Higher School of Economics

Languages

English - Intermediate

Russian - Native

Contact

contact.@kovardaev.com



github.com/kvrdv



@kvrdv

About me

I have 6 years of professional experience in IT, including last 2 years of successful commercial frontend development in fintech sector for a major bank. Proficient in TypeScript, React, Next and a range of latest core frontend technologies. In the past, I have experience in team management as project manager. I am seeking opportunities to apply my experience in creating efficient and user-friendly applications in the role of a frontend developer

Experience

February 2022 - July 2023

Frontend Developer, Gazprombank

Worked in the internal service manager development team. Frontend on React, Material UI styles and components, Node.js middlewares. Security protocols did not allow to use npm packages, code was mostly handwritten. Tasks examples:

- User it assets view feature: fetch data from sql database by user (up to hundreds of records per user), correct display in table (filtering, sorting, selecting), allow export in excel format and print. Select several records from the table and make a request for them (by clicking, open a new view with prefilled selected items data)
- Markdown text editor: text editor with two views, editor with markdown syntax and result
- Links redirect service: about 200 email templates containing links. The link address should depend on what type of user, from which location the action of sending the email was called

January 2020 - February 2022

Chief Manager Information Technology Infrastructure, Domodedovo Airport

Led a team of 3 specialists. Planning, installation, maintenance, personnel recruitment, upgrade of several IT systems, such as:

- CCTV, Physical Access Control system with more then 5 000 units
- Wi-Fi, Ethernet cables for more then 10 000 users
- Automatic barrier systems for car parking

May 2018 - January 2020

Project Manager, Domodedovo Airport

Managed large-scale infrastructure and software projects, overseeing pre-project preparation, procurement, contracting, schedule and budget compliance. Worked in a team with an assistant. Project examples

- First among airports in Russia face recognition system implementation
- Single Sign-On on desktops, Physical Access Control for more then 10 000 users
- CCTV with video and audio analytics, more then 300 camera, video recorder, microphone and data storage units